Dr. Changjiang Cai

Sr. Research Scientist in 3D Vision – InnoPeak Technology, Inc

 \Box +1 (201) 912-1947

☐ changjiangcai2020@gmail.com(primary), ccai1@stevens.edu☑ www.changjiangcai.com☑ in changjiang-cai☑ ccj5351

About

I am serving as a Sr. Research Scientist in 3D Computer Vision at *InnoPeak Technology, Inc,* to solve problems in 3D reconstruction and Augmented Reality via leveraging my knowledge in *Computer Vision* and *Machine Learning*. I obtained my Ph.D. degree of Computer Science from *Stevens Institute of Technology*. Specially, my research interests focus on stereo matching, depth estimation, and 3D reconstruction, as well as human pose estimation and semantic segmentation.

Education

Stevens Institute of Technology

Hoboken, New Jersey, USA

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science, in May 2021

Research Interests: Computer Vision and Machine Learning. Specifically, Stereo Vision, Depth Prediction, 3D reconstruction and Human Mesh Recovery.

Advisor: Philippos Mordohai (https://mordohai.github.io)

Stevens Institute of Technology

Hoboken, New Jersey, USA

 $^{\circ}$ Master of Engineering in Electrical Engineering, in February 2016

Concentration: Computer Vision and Machine Learning.

Advisor: Gang Hua (http://www.ganghua.org)

Xi'an Jiaotong University

Xi'an, Shaanxi, China

Mechanical Engineering

Research Area: Digital Image Processing. Advisor: Dehong Yu

Northwestern Polytechnical University

Xi'an, Shaanxi, China

B.E. in Automobile Engineering, in July 2009

Thesis: Structural Design and 3D Modeling of an Assistive Robot. Advisor: Renping Shao

Publications

Published.....

- Changjiang Cai, Philippos Mordohai. Do End-to-end Stereo Algorithms Under-utilize Information? In International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV), 2020.
- Changjiang Cai, Matteo Poggi, Stefano Mattoccia, and Philippos Mordohai, Matchingspace Stereo Networks for Cross-domain Generalization. In International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV), 2020.

- o Konstantinos Batsos, **Changjiang Cai**, Philippos Mordohai. *CBMV: A coalesced bidirectional matching volume for disparity estimation*. In CVPR 2018, Salt Lake City, Utah, June 2018.
- Changjiang Cai, Haipei Sun, Boxiang Dong, Bo Zhang, Ting Wang, Hui Wang. Pairwise Ranking Aggregation by Non-interactive Crowdsourcing with Budget Constraints. The 37th IEEE International Conference on Distributed Computing (ICDCS), June, 2017, Atlanta, GA.
- Haoxiang Li, Mohammed Kutbi, Xin Li, Changjiang Cai, Philippos Mordohai, Gang Hua, An Egocentric Computer Vision based Co-Robot Wheelchair. IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2016.

Preprints/Submissions.....

o Ren Li, **Changjiang Cai**, Georgios Georgakis, Srikrishna Karanam, Terrence Chen, Ziyan Wu. *Towards Robust RGB-D Human Mesh Recovery*. arXiv:1911.07383.

Research Projects

- [Ongoing] Consistent Dense Depth Estimation from Multi-view Stereo or Monocular Videos
 - Reconstructing geometrically consistent depth for dense pixels in multi-view stereo images or a monocular video via leveraging structure-from-motion to establish geometric constraints among common pixels shared by many views.
- **2021 Project** GCN based Local Expansion for End-to-end MRF Energy Optimization
 - Integrating local α -expansion to GCN for end-to-end solution of MRF energy optimization (e.g., in stereo matching, semantic segmentation and optical flow estimation).
- o **2020 Project** Self-/Un-supervised Robust Presentation Learning
 - Self- or un-supervised learning for a robust representation which aims to improve semantic segmentation, optical flow estimation and monocular or stereo depth estimation.
- o **2020 Project** Do End-to-end Stereo Algorithms Under-utilize Information?
 - Incorporated content-adaptive deep filtering techniques into SOTA networks (including DispNetC, GCNet, PSMNet, and GANet) for improved stereo matching.
- **2019 Project** Matching-space Stereo Networks for Cross-domain Generalization
 - Proposed a novel family of architectures with domain-invariant generalization.
- o **2019 Project** Depth-Aware Human Mesh Recovery
 - Proposed a new method using RGB-D data to estimate a parametric human mesh model
- 2018 Project CBMV_ ROB Entry in the Robust Vision Challenge, CVPR'18 workshop
 - Submitted the CBMV_ROB entry in the stereo challenge, leveraging CBMV volume as in our previous work and local expansion algorithm for optimization.
- o **2017 Project** CBMV: A Coalesced Bidirectional Matching Volume for Disparity Estimation
 - Generated a matching volume by coalescing diverse evidence from a bidirectional matching process via random forest classifiers.
- o **2016 Project Crowdsourcing:** Budget-conscious Ranking by Non-interactive Crowdsourcing
 - Designed a crowdsourced ranking algorithm enabling task requester to obtain a good full ranking result from the crowdsourced pairwise comparison, with a limited budget.
- 2015 Project Epitome Transform Coding: Towards Joint Compression of Images
 - Proposed epitome transform coding, an approach to joint compression of a set of images.

Industry Research Experience

Full-time

Sr. Research Scientist

Part-time intern

Research Intern

Summer intern

Carach Intern

Summer intern

Research Intern

InnoPeak Technology, Inc. Palo Alto, CA

Jun 2021 – Present

Futurewei Technologies, Inc. Seattle, WA

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Futurewei Technologies, Inc. Seattle, WA

May 2020 – *Aug* 2020

UII America, Cambridge, MA

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Teaching Experience

CS442 - Database Management Systems

Teaching Assistant

Stevens Institute of Technology

Aug 2016 – *Dec* 2016

Services

- Reviewer for the following journals:
 - IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP)
 - IEEE Transactions on Multimedia
- Reviewer for the following conferences:
 - ACM Multimedia Conference 2020 (ACMMM'20)
 - ACM Multimedia Conference 2021 (ACMMM'21)
 - AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI'22)

Skills

- **Programming Languages:** Python, C/C++, CUDA, Python& C++ Hybrid, MATLAB
- o Deep Learning: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Caffe
- o Machine Learning: Numpy, Scikit-learn, Scipy, Pandas
- Computer Vision and 3D Geometry: OpenCV, PyTorch Geometric, TensorFlow Graphics
- Other Library & APIs: Matplotlib, Cython, Boost C++
- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL
- o Tools: Vim, Git, CMake, Bash, Tmux, Visual Studio Code, MeshLab, Office, Latex
- OS Platforms: Linux, macOS, Windows

Languages

Chinese (native), English (proficient)

Hobbies

- Playing Basketball, Running and Biking Driving and Road Trip